Kyle Agius

Junior Game Developer

Kyle Agius

13, DiRose, Manuel Bonnici Street, Siggiewi, SGW3082, Malta

Phone: +356 7946 2100 Email: agiuskyle02@gmail.com Portfolio: kyle-agius.github.io

Summary

Recent graduate from a Bachelor's course in software development with first-class honours. Have experience working in a programming role within a team environment. Proficient with the Unity Game Engine through four years of self taught experience.

Work Experience

CS Technologies International / Junior Software Developer

04/08/2022 - 17/09/2022, Paola, Malta

I worked with a small team to convert an Xamarin application to the more recent .NET MAUI framework. This required being able to understand a complex pre-existing system as well as a relatively novel framework. In addition, significant debugging and error handling was needed due to the nature of the task.

CS Technologies International / Junior Software Developer

12/07/2021 - 10/09/2021, Paola, Malta

During the summer break, I worked alongside a small team on a web based project for OneyTrust. During this time, I was able to learn how to make use of various new tools and languages, such as Docker, Python, Angular and Symphony. I was also able to contribute to various features on both the front and back end of the website, making significant improvements to the error validation system.

CS Technologies International / Junior Software Developer

22/07/2019 - 17/09/2019, Paola, Malta

I created a mobile application using Xamarin. The application focused on human resource management and was capable of tracking and approving requests for leave. I was responsible for most of the development of the application, including the design and launch.

CS Technologies International / Junior Software Developer

09/07/2018 - 28/09/2018, Paola, Malta

During my time here, I was able to learn about and make use of the .Net Framework and the C# programming language. I was also able to work on both front and back end web development.

Education

University of Malta / Bachelor of Science in Information Technology (Honours) (Software Development)

12/10/2020 - 21/06/2023, Msida, Malta

The course provided a mixture of practical programming experience alongside professional software development and project management skills. While the programme aimed to be broad in scope, many skills taught are directly applicable to game development.

I graduated with first class honours and received the Dean's Award for high academic merit.

European Qualifications Framework (EQF): Level 6

Lancaster University / ERASMUS Exchange

11/10/2021 - 17/12/2021, Lancaster, United Kingdom

As part of the Bachelor Course, I had the opportunity to study abroad. This gave me a more well rounded understanding of certain crucial topics, such as the SOLID principles. The experience also improved my independent living and time-management skills.

European Qualifications Framework (EQF): Level 6

St. Aloysius College / Matriculation Certificate

24/09/2018 - 25/09/2020, Birkirkara, Malta

I attended sixth form at St. Aloysius College, where I studied the following subjects:

Advanced Level: Pure Mathematics, Physics

Intermediate Level: English. Economics, Information Technology, Systems of Knowledge

European Qualifications Framework (EQF): Level 4

Experience in Game Development

Self Taught Experience using the Unity Engine

01/08/2019 - Current

Practised game development in Unity for several years alongside full-time studies. Online resources are used for skill acquisition. Emphasis is placed on clean, maintainable and efficient code. In addition to programming, I practised 2D art and game design, which should aid communication between roles.

Use of Unity in my Thesis Project

26/09/2022 - 21/06/2023

For part of my thesis project, I was able to create a fast system that mimics real-time style transfer in games for both 2D and 3D scenarios without the need of complex hardware. For 2D, this was done by loading and swapping stylised sprites. This was extended for 3D by stylising the textures applied to a model.

I created this system in the Unity Game Engine with a focus on speed and efficiency. The final result achieved the desired goals for both scenarios.

Participation in a Game Jam

12/08/2022 - 15/08/2022

I took part in the "Wowie Jam 4.0", hosted on Itch.io. Here, I was able to create a simple, story focused game. This was relatively well received, being ranked 191st from 1019 entrees.

Except for the music and sound effects, all aspects of this project were made solely by me. While the game has room for improvement, it does showcase my range of skills, my ability to work in a limited time period and being able to handle unexpected issues.

Followed a Degree+ Unit about Unity 3D

06/11/2020 - 15/01/2021

Followed an optional University unit titled "Creating Virtual Worlds" about creating 3D scenes in Unity. While the unit was entry level in nature and focused on the fundamentals, I found it helpful as I had only worked on 2D games up to this point.